Is it ever a good idea to ramp up your experiment?
是否它曾是个好主意 强化了你的实验？
That is, maybe you start with 1% of your traffic as being
或许你的流量最开始只有 1%
diverted to the experiment group, but
作为实验组
then you gradually increase that until your feature is fully launched.
然后逐渐增加 直到所有性能全部发布
>> Actually, I think it's good practice to always do a ramp-up
实际上 我认为逐渐增加是个好方法
when you actually want to launch a change.
当你需要发布一个变化时
In fact, we do that for all of our launches at Google.
事实上 我们在 Google 就是这样做的
The other thing that we do is that we remove all of the filters.
我们做的另一件事是 去掉所有的筛选
So if you're only testing your change on English, for example,
如果你只用英语测试变化
you want to test your change during your ramp-up on all users.
例如 你想要测试变化 在对所有用户上逐渐增加
Because what you want to know is if there's been any incidental impact to
因为你想要知道 是否对没有受到影响的用户有偶然影响
unaffected users that you didn't test in the original experiment.
那是你在原始实验中没有测试的
Now, there's one interesting complication or
现在 有一个有趣的新问题
gotcha that we do have to deal with in our ramp-up wherein so
我们必须处理逐渐更新的事情
that the effect may actually flatten out as you ramp up the change.
以至于影响可能会消失 随着你不断更新这些变化
>> Wait, even if the initial effect was statically significant?
稍等 即使最开始的影响具有统计学上的意义
I thought the point of statistical significance is that your results will
我认为统计显著性的要点是
be repeatable.
结果可能重复出现
>> Well, there can be some really simple reasons as to why the effects are not
有一些非常简单的原因
repeatable.
对于为什么影响不是重复的
For example, there's all sorts of seasonality effects.
例如 各种季节性影响
Students, for example.
例如 学生
When students go on summer vacation,
当学生过暑假时
the behavior across broad swaths of the Internet changes.
网络行为会发生变化
And when they come back from vacation, it changes again.
当他们假期结束以后 会再次发生变化
There might be other seasonal effects like holidays.
还有其他诸如假期的季节性影响
Everyone's heard of Black Friday and Cyber Monday.
每个人都听说过黑色星期五和网购星期一
So shopping behavior can change a lot around the holidays.
在这些假期 购买行为会有很大变化
Now, one way to try and capture these seasonal or
尝试和抓住这些季节性或者事件驱动的影响
event-driven impacts is something that we call a holdback.
一种方式被我们称之为控制
And the idea is that you launch your change to everyone except for
理念就是把变化发布给每个人 除了一个小的控制
a small holdback, or, basically, a set of users, that don't get the change, and
或者 一组没有发现变化的用户
you continue comparing their behavior to the control.
继续把他们的行为比作是控制
Now, in that case you should see the reverse of
在那种情况下 你会看到
the impact that you saw in your experiment.
与实验中发现的相反的影响
And what you can do is you can track that over time until you're confident
你能做的就是你可以对它进行实时追踪
that your results are actually repeatable.
直到你相信结果实际上是重复的
And that can really help capture a lot of your seasonal or
那真的能帮你捕捉到许多季节性或者
event-driven impacts.
事件驱动型影响
>> Okay, is there anything else that can cause this disappearing launch effect?
还有其他能消除发布影响的事情吗？
>> Well, we've talked about this a couple times in the other lessons but
我们已经在其他课程中多次谈到了这个问题
there can be a novelty effect or change aversion.
但是这里可能有一个新影响或者变化版本
Those humans they're so troublesome.
这些人非常麻烦
They keep changing their behavior, right?
他们的行为不断发生变化
But as users discover or adopt or
但是当用户发现或者接受或者
change their adoption of your change, then their behavior can change and
改变对变化的接受情况时 他们的行为会发生变化
therefore the measured effects can change.
因此 测试到的影响会发生变化
And this is where a cohort analysis can really be helpful.
这就是组群分析能真正产生效用的地方
Now, another situation that may also happen is that if you have advertisers
另一个可能发生的情况是
that have budgets, a lot of times, if you don't control for
如果你的广告商有预算 时间充裕
the budgets properly, the effect can change as you ramp up.
如果你没有合理控制预算 在你逐步改变的时候 实验效应会发生变化
>> Okay, and how would I catch things like this during the experiment,
在实验过程中 我应该如何抓住这些
rather than after the launch has happened and something went wrong?
而不是在发布了以后或者一些东西出了问题以后
>> This is where you get into the more complicated analyses and
这里需要用到更加复杂的分析法
in the more complicated experiment designs.
和更复杂的实验设计
We had talked in lesson four about using pre- and post-periods.
我们在第四课中谈到了使用周期前和周期后
And so if you're really concerned about a learning effect,
所以 如果你真的在意学习效果
you probably want to use those pre- and
你可能想要使用这些周期前和周期后
those post-periods, combined with a cohort analysis, to try and
和组群分析
understand how your users are basically adapting to the change over time.
尝试理解你的用户是如何随时间流逝适应改变的